This video introduces the range pull function for you.
Starting from the 2025 version, when you press and pull the clothing in the simulation mode,
the area and strength of the support for pull are defined, and the exact adjustment is made according to the needs.
Now it shows several application scenarios for range pull.
For single-layer clothing, we can make small-range twist details through the range pull function.
You can also make relatively large-range suit back adjustment.
When you modify the posture, you can use the range pull to adjust the waist with a multi-layer structure.
Next, let's take a look at how to use it.
To use the range pull, we need to open the simulation first.
Once the simulation is opened, select the move tool to switch to the small-handle point pull tool.
At this time, we press the point pull tool for two seconds, and we can see the tool group.
Press the range pull tool to move the mouse to the 3D window of the clothing.
You can see that on the basis of the original grip, two new circles have been added.
This is our range brush.
It can help you directly understand the range of the influence of the range pull.
In addition, we can also see that there is a range pull window setting.
The window setting is divided into two main contents, range and options.
First, let's look at the range.
The reduction type below the range is controlled by the shape of the pull effect.
You can switch it to a curve or a straight line.
The range of soft selection and the degree of reduction separately control the range of influence when the pull is pulled and the range of the center point.
The smaller inner circle in the two circles indicates the area where the pull effect is most directly applied.
As the effect is radiated outward, the strength gradually decreases, resulting in a smooth natural reduction.
The range of soft selection is controlled by the area affected by the pull.
As the value increases, the size of the two circles on the clothing will also be expanded accordingly.
The default value is 200, and it can be adjusted within the range of 1 to 500.
The degree of reduction is controlled from the core area of the pull to the maximum range of influence.
The default value is 0, and it can be adjusted within the range of 2 to 2.
The chart area below can help you understand more objectively.
When the reduction type is a curve, the pull selection area is not a single pull, but a smoother, rounder, and wider shape.
Next, let's use the curve as an example to see the effect.
Let's use the default value of the pull sleeve first.
Change the soft selection range to 250.
Turn to the back of the suit to pull.
You will see that the pull effect is more effective in the area where the same core is defined.
This time, let's set the soft selection range to 500 and pull the clothing.
Compared to before, the area covered by the inner circle and the outer circle is now twice as wide.
You can pull a larger area.
Now let's set the value to be the smallest.
Then pull the panel again.
The soft selection range is only 1 mm.
This allows us to make a very small range of pull.
Next, we will change the soft selection range to 200.
And set the reduction degree to the smallest value to 2.
Then pull.
In this case, the inner circle almost overlaps with the outer circle.
The pull effect is evenly distributed in a larger area, rather than concentrated on a specific point.
Finally, let's set the maximum value to 2 and pull the clothes again.
Through the chart below, you can see that the pull force is highly concentrated at a specific point.
This means that accurate operation is performed in small areas.
Next, we will adjust the reduction degree to 1.
The reduction type is modified to a straight line.
The straight line allows you to define a smaller and more detailed core area to be squeezed.
After switching to the straight line option, you will notice that the picture becomes sharper and sharper.
At this time, when you pull the clothes, you will find that the selection range of the core area is narrower and more accurate than the curve line.
So you can control the pull correctly.
You can choose the reduction type according to your preferences.
Next, let's take a look.
How to display and control the pull selection area.
At the bottom of the option, the range measurement method defines how to calculate the selection area from the actual point.
It is divided into two types, the surface and the straight line.
In the surface mode, the pull effect is only applicable to the surface of a selected layer within the specified range.
Even if there are multiple layers here, it is the same.
However, when the pull and the strip are sewed together, any soft selection range that is defined and the area within the reduction range will be affected at the same time.
The straight line option allows you to pull all the sheets within a certain distance.
Whether the selected sheet is sewed together with the sheets of other layers,
when you use this option to pull the sheet, you will see that all the sheets within the defined range are affected at the same time.
The range brush display can help you to understand the range of the pull function more objectively.
You can also turn off the range brush display here.
Now let's take a look at the use of each range measurement method.
The range brush display is only used for the effect of pulling the area when selecting the selected sheet.
As you can see, whether it is the surface or the straight line,
as a range measurement method and only used for selecting the selected sheet,
when the range brush is turned over, it will only affect the currently selected turned over sheet.
When you want to pull a specific sheet in the given work process,
no matter which range measurement method you choose, this option is very useful.
Next, when the full weight function is used,
the range brush display will display the pull area in green.
If you turn off this option, the range brush display will no longer display the area in green,
but it will not affect the effect of the range brush.
The range brush is not only used to adjust the overall effect of the clothes,
but it can also help to quickly adjust various details such as knotting and knotting.
First, re-position the fixed needle and prepare for the knotting.
Then select the range brush tool and adjust the range and the degree of reduction according to the area size of the brush.
After the setting is complete, turn to the appropriate angle,
pull the clothes to complete the knotting details.
After achieving the desired effect, delete the fixed needle and continue to simulate.
Then the introduction of the range brush function is here,
I hope this function can help you quickly adjust the ideal clothing effect.